Wash It
All Away
Episode 12        Local Cleaning with a Heart
Um, may I ask you to take care of this?
Of course.
Thank you very much.
Please allow me to inspect the garment.
You two sure are dressed up today.
Are you going somewhere together?
Yes, to Izu.
To stay the night!
I'm going to take a bunch of pictures
and draw sketches of capybaras,
crocodiles, and bananas!
Huh? Do those things go together?
I'll bring you back a souvenir,
so please expect something nice!
All right.
A trip sounds nice. I'd love to go
somewhere far away for a change.
Are you plotting to skip town, then?
Ah! Aji-san?
Yeah, just kidding.
Here.
Take care of these.
Thank you very much. Allow me to
inspect your items at the counter.
Again? It's the same stuff as always.
You don't need to check every
single time. For crying out loud.
No, I must! No matter how carefully
you handle your clothes,
they may become worn or discolored,
or stretch or shrink over time.
Buttons and seams can unravel, and you
might have stains that aren't easy to see.
That is why I must check
every single time!
Ugh.
Oh, I'm sorry.
I didn't mean to come across as pushy.
Fine, then. Do it your way.
Orders will be ready
on the 26th
How long has it been since
you set up here. Two years?
Yes.
Right, right.
And you're still using
the same old ironing table.
Yes, I am. I try to take good care of
the equipment passed down to me.
I'm glad you're able to
make use of such an antique.
It's all because you maintained
everything, Aji-san.
I didn't maintain a thing.
I just left it all alone.
What's taking so long?
Um, Aji-san, excuse me, but would you
mind if I asked you something?
What now? Is it about the rent?
Fine, then. If it's that much of a hassle,
I'll just wash it myself.
Uh, that's not what I meant.
I simply wanted to...
Huh?
Orders will be ready
on the 8th
And he ran off without saying a word?
Yes.
Huh? What? Kyusho-kun?
I wonder if I did something
to make him uncomfortable.
Of course not. Don't even worry about it.
I'm sure he was just embarrassed.
Embarrassed?
Well, sure.
We're talking about a boy who's still
making his way through puberty, right?
Oh, come on, Kinme-san!
I wonder if you're right.
I am. So you don't need to worry.
Kinme
Timer
Start
Pause
We are closed for the day.
September Rent
Kinme Wakana
Kinme Cleaning
She usually comes to pick it up
at the end of the month.
Um, Aji-san, excuse me but would you
mind if I asked you something?
What now? Is it about the rent?
Um, Aji-san, how have you
been feeling recently?
Huh? What are you talking about?
You know what I say.
I've always been healthy as a horse.
Hmph!
I noticed something similar the last time
you brought your laundry in,
but there appears to be a stain
in the crotch area I hadn't seen before.
Could this mean...
Fine, then. If it's that much of a hassle,
I'll just wash it myself.
I must have offended her.
What do I do now?
September Rent
Kinme Wakana
Kinme Cleaning
Away for a moment.
Be back soon. - Manager
So this is Aji-san's house.
Absolutely NO Solicitors
Door-to-Door Sales Prohibited
I know she always says she doesn't
want me showing up at her house.
Excuse me, please. It's me, Kinme Wakana.
Are you home, Aji-san?
I wonder if she's out.
It's open?
Excuse me, please.
It's me, Kinme Wakana.
Oh, Aji-san!
I'm sorry to catch you
while you're cleaning.
I went ahead and
brought this month's rent.
Wash It All Away
We pick up and deliver!
Kinme Cleaning
All right, move along now.
How am I gonna get
any sweeping done? Sheesh.
I guess all these leaves
mean it's finally fall.
Yes, I suppose it is
that time of the year.
Getting out of the house
is gonna be a pain now.
Boy oh boy.
I brought your clean garments for you.
Appreciate it.
I was able to get
the stains out completely.
Were you now? Thank you.
Yeah, that sure was embarrassing.
All the while, I kept saying,
"I'm healthy as a horse!"
But you read me like a book and
knew what was wrong, didn't you?
Well, I wouldn't put it that way.
I am very sorry for upsetting you, though.
I should not have spoken so carelessly.
It's all right. If you hadn't been worried
about me, I might not have made it.
When I felt myself starting to pass out,
I thought that was it for me.
I should've listened to your warning
and gotten checked at the hospital
instead of ignoring it
until I ended up collapsing.
I wouldn't call it a warning. I wasn't
aware of your condition, after all.
It's just, the longer I get to know my
customers as their neighborhood cleaner,
I do start to notice when there are
slight changes in their garments.
And I'll think, "Oh, it looks like
her weight changed a little"
or "He must have gone through something
that made him sweat a lot."
I really only wanted to share
with you what I had noticed.
You're like a criminal profiler,
in a manner of speaking.
Pro-what?
Well, I just mean to say
that people who work as cleaners
actually have a pretty important job.
I agree!
Speaking of which, your shop is
two years old now, isn't it?
Ah, yes! I couldn't have
made it without you.
Oh boy, I remember how
stressful things were at first
when you didn't have many customers.
I was so afraid that you might not
make rent, it gave me the chills.
Yes, I remember that.
But I was soon able to build a regular
customer base thanks to your advice.
You told me that because of all
the hills and stairs in this town,
there are elderly folks who can't get
to my shop even if they want to.
And with all of the winding, narrow roads,
it can be tough getting
around even in a car.
When I heard that, I thought, "Okay,
I need to think of a way to serve
this community's needs."
That's why...
I decided the shop motto should be
"Local Cleaning with a Heart."
Seems fitting.
So, are you planning anything special
for your second anniversary?
Oh, yes!
I was thinking of throwing a special
second anniversary event
to show my appreciation
to all of my customers.
Oh. Sounds nice.
Well then, I'll be going.
When it's too much trouble to leave
the house, I'll give you another call.
Sure! Whenever you need me.
Aji-san, what's the matter?
I never expected that it
would be my turn next.
Your turn next?
Well, I remembered I'd heard about
something like this in the past
from the cleaning shop
that was in there before you.
Oh.
The manager then also noticed
a change in a customer's clothes
that meant their disease was progressing.
Thanks to that,
they caught it just in time.
Hmm...
So the previous cleaner paid
attention to things like that too.
Hello, this is Kinme Cleaning.
Oh, Yagara-san?
Huh? Tonight?
Well, yes, I'm free.
You want me to play?
All right!
Ready!
Go for it!
Asami!
Okay!
I got one!
You sure did, Yagara-san!
Nikko-tei
Grand Bath
Phew! Yeah.
You sure saved our necks today!
One of our members got busy
with something at the last minute.
But since you stepped in, we were
still able to play a scrimmage.
And you're actually pretty good!
Oh, no. I was just following
everyone else's lead.
I always knew you'd be good at sports.
We barely taught you anything and
you're already playing like a regular.
Oh, I wouldn't say that.
We'd love it if you joined formally.
Well, I'm not even married yet, so...
You're still young, so I bet you
don't even get sore muscles.
Yeah, if I don't cool down afterwards,
I'm stiff as a board the next day!
I wish I could work out
as much as Yagara-chan does.
Yagara-chan, show us that again!
Working on this is just a hobby of mine.
Just look at those abs!
I'm so jealous.
You're in great shape too, Kinme-san.
Your skin is so supple.
I can't help but be jealous!
Wow!
And so firm.
Hey, let me feel!
I'll return the uniform
after I've washed it.
No, you can keep it.
Huh?
Save it for the next time
I invite you, all right?
Uh...
See you.
Yeah.
Oh, almost forgot. I'll bring you
my husband's suit tomorrow.
So do your usual thing to it, okay?
Sure. As usual, you can count on Kinme.
Mm-hmm!
Well, that was an overwhelming day.
But this is one great way
to stay active in the community.
And you're still using
the same old ironing table.
I wonder what kind of person
the previous manager was.
2-Year Anniversary
Discount Sale
30% Off Coupon
* Please present this flyer when visiting.
Thanks to your support, our business is
entering its third year. We continue to
follow our motto to bring you
"local cleaning with a heart"
and will always do our best
to make our customers happy.
Manager: Kinme Wakana
We pick up
and deliver!
Kinme
Cleaning
Guesthouse Inn Ishimochi
Good evening! It's Kinme Cleaning.
I've come to deliver your garments.
Hey!
Thanks a lot. I'm sorta tied up right now,
so can you leave them by the door?
Oh, sure!
I'm doing a second anniversary event,
so I'll leave a flyer for that as well.
It's your second anniversary!
Well, we'll have to celebrate, then.
Oh, that isn't necessary.
Oh, but I want to!
You're always such a lifesaver.
I'll stop by with a present in a few days.
Thank you very much!
Uka-san?
Wakana-san?
I can tell Konatsu and Dai are thrilled
to bump into you this morning.
I am too, of course.
I'm flattered.
I'm happy to see you all too.
Oh. I heard from the ladies
at the bath house,
but congratulations on your shop's
second anniversary!
We should celebrate sometime.
Celebrate?
This is a big deal,
so on your next day off,
why don't you come over again
for some more homemade cooking?
Oh, yes! I'd love to.
Come on in.
Who may I help first?
Oh, it's all right.
We didn't bring any laundry today.
Mm-hmm.
Huh?
Here. In honor of your second anniversary.
Huh? I can't...
No, really. Please take it.
Thank you very much.
I really appreciate it!
Well, it makes us very happy to hear that.
Keep up the good work. We appreciate you.
Yes, we do.
We do.
Thank you! I'll continue to do my best.
See you next time.
Those are such pretty flowers!
Orders will be ready
on the 25th
They're a present
for my shop's anniversary.
But of course!
Oh, I also brought you a present!
Here it is.
It's a second anniversary card!
Kinme-oneesan
Congratulations
Katakuchi
Nairo
Pssht
Nairo-chan! Thank you so much!
Allow me to take a second
anniversary picture for publicity!
I'll post it soon.
Thank you for handling all that.
Kinme-san!
Wassup.
Oh, hello.
Kinme-san, do you have a moment?
Sure.
We brought this.
Ready and...
Congratulations on your
second anniversary!
Huh? Is that for me?
Yeah!
Can I open it right now?
Of course!
2nd Anniversary
Kinme
Cleaning
Wow!
Thank you so much!
I'm so flattered to have you all here
to celebrate with me.
What?
No, you already got cake?
Yagara-san!
Yeah, but you can
never have too much cake!
You're right about that!
Mm-hmm!
Who are you, anyway?
Um... I'm Moruda.
2nd Anniversary
Kinme
Cleaning
Kinme-san
Congratulations
Translation:
Editing/Typesetting:
Michael Arnold
Ashley Barboza
Quality Control:
Translation Check:
Riley Dalton
Sriram Gurunathan
Here are your washed garments.
Well, thanks.
So how's the second anniversary
event going?
Fine. I thought it would be a nice way to
show my appreciation for my customers,
but I ended up receiving
a bunch of gifts instead.
I'm honestly starting
to feel a little guilty.
Why would you feel guilty about that?
Huh?
It's just a way to show their gratitude
for how considerate you always are.
You shouldn't be ashamed to accept it.
All right.
Oh, that reminds me.
Would you wait right there a minute?
Oh...
Here. This one is from me.
If you don't need it,
you can toss it for all I care.
Thank you so much!
It has already been two years
since I started my shop in this city.
When I was just starting out,
I didn't have many regular customers,
and there were times
when I was unsure of the future.
But over time, people got to
know me and my business better,
and as a result,
I've been able to make it this far.
I'll keep striving to live up
to my motto to provide
"Local Cleaning with a Heart."
Welcome. I'll get the door right away.
All right.
Is this your first time coming here?
Yes. Someone in the neighborhood
recommended you.
I think I this got dirty when
I was out with friends yesterday.
I see.
Please allow me to inspect your item.
Sure.
It's a favorite that
my mother bought for me.
Do you think you can clean it?
You can count on Kinme.
Thank you for watching.